<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Moderation on community.datasci.social</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/tags/moderation/</link><description>Recent content in Moderation on community.datasci.social</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 17:36:37 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://community.datasci.social/tags/moderation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moderation</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/docs/moderation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://community.datasci.social/docs/moderation/</guid><description>Team All moderation and administration is done by our volunteer admin(istrator) and mod(erator) team:
Name Handle Role Ben F. Maier @benfmaier Admin Erika Legara @eflegara Mod Esteban Moro @estebanmoro Mod Lucio La Cava @luciolcw Admin Michael Szell @mszll Admin Silvia De Sojo Caso @sdesojo Mod Our admin contact email is: datasci.social@proton.me
Individual-based moderation To report a post, click on the three dots below the post and select “Report”. Please include all relevant context to help us process the report.</description></item><item><title>Server rules</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/docs/server-rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://community.datasci.social/docs/server-rules/</guid><description>This page should always be held in sync with the server rules and therefore be edited only by an admin, so the github change log of this page serves as a rule change log.
Don&amp;rsquo;t be a jerk. We expect to treat each other respectfully. No racism, sexism, homophobia, transphobia, xenophobia, or casteism No incitement of violence or promotion of violent ideologies No harassment, dogpiling, doxxing, or impersonation No content that is considered illegal in Denmark or France No intentional sharing of false or misleading information No spam or commercial advertisements Nothing NSFW (not safe for work), such as sexually explicit or violent media SIGN-UP: This is not a generalist server and is destined for professionals in human-centric data science, broadly defined.</description></item><item><title>Our stance on Threads</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-12-17/our-stance-on-threads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 14:57:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-12-17/our-stance-on-threads/</guid><description>With Meta&amp;rsquo;s Threads recently starting concrete federation experiments, we have been asked about datasci.social&amp;rsquo;s stance concerning preemptive suspension (also called &amp;ldquo;defederation&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;fediblock&amp;rdquo;).
Here my (Michael&amp;rsquo;s) short answer:
Has datasci.social suspended or limited the threads.net domain?
No.
Will datasci.social suspend or limit the threads.net domain?
Possibly, if/whenever necessary. We are closely monitoring the situation.
Long answer: Given Meta&amp;rsquo;s abysmal history with surveillance capitalism and human rights it is reasonable to consider Threads a bad faith actor, meaning that its activities should be assumed to underlie as exploitative as possible motives.</description></item><item><title>One year old</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-11-17/one-year-old/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-11-17/one-year-old/</guid><description>One year ago, datasci.social was created! 🥳🎂 In this time datasci.social has become a vibrant online community with 286 people who have joined from all over the world, from various disciplines or from industry, providing an online home for the data science community, broadly defined. Explore our awesome stream here: https://datasci.social/public/local
There has been smooth, mostly constant growth over the past year, and luckily we have been facing no moderative or technical challenges.</description></item><item><title>New admin</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-04-28/new-admin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 10:26:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-04-28/new-admin/</guid><description>One more admin joined our team today: Lucio La Cava (@luciolcw)
Lucio is a researcher researching the social network of Mastodon, so he has particular insights into the system.
We still had zero moderative reports on our server so far, and we have a calm pace of new sign-ups. Therefore, there is currently no necessity to extend our team, but we want to be well prepared for a possible flood of sign-ups in case other, larger online social networks collapse.</description></item><item><title>100 members</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-02-27/100-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-02-27/100-members/</guid><description>We have reached 100 members on https://datasci.social! 🥳
Since opening registrations in Jan with 50 members we have doubled in size, following a nice pace of growth. We are now also steadily posting over 100 new posts/week.
With ample capacity to grow, we encourage everyone interested in data science, network science, computational social science, and related fields to join us, or to spread the word about our place. Although we have 5 mods/admins, we still had no single moderative report so far.</description></item><item><title>Registrations opened</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-01-12/registrations-opened/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-01-12/registrations-opened/</guid><description>🚨 Registrations at datasci.social are now open! Sign up here: https://datasci.social/auth/sign_up
How to migrate your account: https://mstdn.social/@feditips/107939441820299376
Before doing so, let us clarify our philosophy and roadmap:
The present and future of datasci.social The instance was set up on Nov 17, 2022, for this reason:
The goal of this server is to create a community of nice and diverse people who are researching human-centric data science and adjacent topics. For example human-centric data/network science, social data science, urban/geospatial data science, computational social science.</description></item><item><title>New team, roadmap, community pages</title><link>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-01-06/new-team-roadmap-community-pages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 11:42:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://community.datasci.social/blog/2023-01-06/new-team-roadmap-community-pages/</guid><description>In preparation for opening datasci.social registrations next week, some news 🚨
New mod/admin team: https://community.datasci.social/docs/moderation/ @benfmaier @eflegara @estebanmoro @sdesojo Not a single report so far, but good to be prepared.
We adhere to the Mastodon covenant: https://joinmastodon.org/covenant
Roadmap: https://community.datasci.social/docs/roadmap/
Community pages: https://community.datasci.social/docs, with info on management, moderation, security, server. Check it out! #mastoadmin #serverinfo
Stay tuned for opening news!
[Post copied from https://datasci.social/@mszll/109641856876435648]</description></item></channel></rss>